Yohei Suzuki

Profile

An online marketing manager who have retrained to be a UX designer/Researcher. Have Advanced skills in analyzing date, landing page research and planning. Familiar with technical projects, having affinity and passion for IT and new technology. Positive thinker with problem-solving and analytical skill, Multitask worker. Highly motivated and interested in learning new computer software and new capabilities.

Contact

yohei.suzuki.de@gmail.com

+49 176 3137 0648

Obentrautstr 43 10963

Berlin Germany

Linkedin.com/in/yohei-s

Skills

Language

- Japanese Native
- English Fluent
- German Working level

UX Research & Design

- User Research
- Usability Analysis
- Creating User
 Personas
- Journey Mapping
- Information
 Architecture
- Prototyping and Wireframing
- Usability testing and AB testing
- HTML & CSS
- JavaScript

Experience

PPC Manager 2017 July-Present

Peak Ace AG, Berlin

Support the creation and optimization of paid search campaigns, keyword research and the creation and optimization of ad copies, conduct competitor analyses for clients from various industries, support with the creation of reports and interpretation of KPIs.

Translator, Localization Manager......2007-Present **Freelance**

Able to translate 2k-3k words per day for complex contents. Managing, budget controlling the entire life cycle of localization, translation and proofreading projects. Staffing freelance vendors, preparing project documentation, quality management, account management, and acquire customers. Worked for several companies via agencies and direct deal, including:

Google, Amazon.com, Intel, Booking.com (Average 20k+ words per week), Spotify.com (Launching contents), EBEL, Wonderfulexpo2015.info (Italian tourism site), Philips, and many more.

Online Media Analyst 2015-2016

Gorkana - Freelance

Provide analytics report of a specific brand on online and offline media with using analytics tools.

Community Online Marketing Manager ---- 2010-2013 Swerford holdings - Gibraltar

As a Community Manager for Marketing, Localization for 19 Multilingual website called pokerstrategy.com, which has a massive table of contents with a fast-paced start-up environment. The company is a very successful affiliate marketing company, have gained very outstanding affiliate marketing knowledge and extensive community management skill.

Skills

Online Marketing Skills

- Google Ads certificates,
 Google Ad editor,
 Google Analytics,
 Google Tag Manager
- SEO Keyword research
- SEO On-Page
 Optimization
- SEMrush
- Link Building
- Competitor Analysis
- Bid Management
- Campaign Optimization
- Performance Analysis

Tools

- Sketch
- Photoshop
- Illustrator
- InVision
- MS Office (Excel, Word, Power point)
- Trados, Memo Q
- Google AD editor
- Google Analytics

Customer Support Representative ------2009-2010

Provided support service to the members via email, phone and live chat on a range of issues; such as game enquiries, helping with deposits, cashing out of funds etc. in English and Japanese. Archived 20+ support issues to be solved per day. Offered upsell to get a deposit from the members. translated Japanese to English and vice versa for the Support Department, and any other department in the company.

Technical / Service Support 2007-2008 Hi-bit K.K and N.T.T, Tokyo

Provided support service to the customers via email, phone, on a range of issues; such as Technical issues, service issues, handling customer's complaints, pressing overdue payments. Also responsible for upsell campaign.

Label Manager, Festival Director 2001-2006

Label Manager, Festival Director- Tokyo

Label Manager, Festival Director~ Led a team to achieve festival success. Greatly influenced the market by indoor event "Stargate" & outdoor festival "Utage", which had audiences count up to 5000.

- ~CD, Vinyl Distributor~ Distributed music media like CDs, and vinyl for a Japanese market.
- ~Media Design & Promotion~ Created a media design for a flyer, album cover, website

Education

888.com, Gibraltar

CareerFoundry 2018.10-2020.3

UserExperience design course-Berlin

Intensive project-based training program with a focus on UserExperience Design. Designed a mobile web app, by Prototyping, wireframing using Sketch and Invision. View project here: behance.net/gallery/94056827/EXpert

Tech:Camp 2016.8

iOS Swift developer course-Tokyo

Intensive project-based Bootcamp program with a focus on iOS development with Swift.

Digital Hollywood Technical school ------2007

WebMaster course, HTML and CSS

Kanto Gakuin University 2000-2004

Economics, Yokohama